I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
even though I love you so much
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
You said we should break up
Mou wakareyou to
Kimi no koe ga kikoeta shunkan
and when I heard that
my world turned white in an instant
Mou masshiro ni natte
Karadajuu ni hashitta hibana
and sparks danced in my vision
Is forgetting you what I need
Kimi no koto wo wasureru koto ga
Mae ni susundeku koto na no?
to move on?
I could cry now, I don't understand
Wakaranai yo nakete kuru yo
Let's live in the moment, only in the moment
Seiippai meiippai ima wo ikiyou
We lived like that until now, too, I guess
Sou yatte ikite kita kedo
I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
even though I love you so much
（左門）早河
そちらの作業は進んでいるか？
Hayakawa,
how are things progressing on your end?
（早河・通信）絶園の魔法使いが
御柱への攻撃を→
I've already leaked information
that the mage of Exodus plans to attack the Pillar.
画策しているという情報は
すでに流した。
（早河）
現場にいる艦が　どう対応するか→
I'm certain the fleet will decide to respond,
ある程度の意志統一は
図られているだろう。
at least in some way.
（左門・通信）ある程度か…。
To an extent?
Ultimately, it depends on how things go,
（早河）結局　出たとこ勝負だろうが
死ぬなよ。
so be careful.
（左門・通信）己の行いを顧みれば→
Considering my past actions,
このあたりで　それくらいの報いを
受けそうだがな。
I imagine things might finally catch up with me.
ふっ
行いが悪いのは　お互いさまだ。
We're in this together, you know.
お前に　ぶざまに死なれると→
If you suffer a gruesome death,
こちらも将来が心配になる。
ふっ。
I'll have to worry about my own future.
フロイラインたちは
すでに日本を出て→
The Fräulein's group has since left Japan.
船や供物の手配中だ。
They requisitioned a ship and some offerings.
Junichiro and I will be leaving tomorrow, along with the princess and Hanemura.
私と潤一郎は　姫様と羽村を伴い→
明日には出立する。　そして→
Fuwa Mahiro and Takigawa Yoshino will be coming as well.
不破真広と滝川吉野も共にな。
（早河・通信）何ぃ!?
What?!
Episode 23
Battle of Genesis
≫ガチャ（ドアの音）
（不破真広）おう　呼んだか？
You wanted something?
（羽村）あっ　あの…。
あっ？
Um...
真広君
もし　僕に何かあったら…。
Mahiro, if anything happens to me,
can you mail this for me?
（羽村）これを出してほしいんだ！
振られた彼女宛てか？
To that girl who dumped you?
うん。　無事に帰って来れたら→
Yeah.
It won't be necessary if I come back in one piece, but...
必要ないんだけど…。
はぁ～。
なっ　なんてことするんだい！→
H-How could you?!
It took me three whole days to write that.
書くのに３日かかったのに～！
Listen.
あのな　お前に何かあったら
その時点で　世界は終わりだ。
If anything happens to you, the world is doomed anyway.
If you have something to say to her, stay alive and tell her yourself.
言いたいことがあるなら
生きて帰って　直接　言え。
だけどさ
映画の主人公みたいに→
But I might end up like a movie hero,
捨て身の攻撃で　はじまりの樹に
勝利するって展開もあるだろう!?→
launching a final, desperate attack on the Tree and actually succeeding!
You know, both sides taking each other out.
ほら　相打ちってやつだよ！
お前は
映画の主人公じゃねぇだろ。
You're not a movie hero.
捨て身の攻撃で負けたらどうする。
What if that last-ditch effort doesn't work?
死んだら意味がねぇんだよ。
Dying is meaningless.
（羽村）真広君…。
Mahiro...
((はぁ　はぁ…))
（山本）
((どうしたの？　二人して改まって))
What's wrong?
Both of you look so serious.
（滝川吉野）
((僕たちも　御柱破壊チームに→
We'd like to join the Pillar assault team.
入れてほしいんです))
（羽村）((ええ～!?→
Eh?!
Ow! Ow, ow, ow...
うわ～　痛っ　痛っ！　痛ててっ！))
（山本）((御柱近くでは
鎖部の魔法は使えないうえに→
You already know Kusaribe magic won't work near the Pillar.
秘密裏に
御柱近海へ近づかねばならない。→
Plus, this has to be a covert operation.
行動しやすい少人数が望まれるの))
((はっきり言えよ))
The smaller the group, the better.
Just cut to the chase.
((あなたたちは　足手まといよ))
((言ってくれるな))
You'd hold us back.
That's harsh.
((僕たちのことは
放置してもらってかまいません))
You don't need to keep us safe.
((命の危険にあっても→
Even if we get into danger, don't try to save us.
助けは不要です))
（葉風）((そんな…))
But that's—
Taking you near the Pillar is too risky.
（山本）((さすがに
御柱付近に連れていくのは危険よ))
（葉風）((ほかの鎖部の者たちは→
The other Kusaribe members are guarding the Tree of Exodus.
絶園の樹を
見張ることになっている。→
二人は　そちらに…))
((すみません))
You two should help with that.
I'm sorry,
((でも　僕は
何かが起ころうとしている→
but I know something big is about to happen,
その中心に行きたいんです))
（葉風）((吉野！))
and I want to be there when it does.
Yoshino!
You guys are using my plan.
It only makes sense that I take the lead on this.
((だったら
責任者を連れていくのは当然だ))
Am I wrong?
((違うか？))
（山本）((真広君の作戦は→
It's not as though your plan was particularly great.
誰しも考えられる選択肢の
一つよ。→
We only settled on it because we had nothing better.
結局　それしかないから
受け入れただけ…))
And the one who decided we had nothing better was me.
((それしかないを決定したのは
俺だろ？))
((はぁ～　まったく　あんたは…。→
Jeez, you're such a...
本当に放っておくわよ。
泣いても知らないからね))
We really will leave you guys behind.
You'd better not regret this.
Thank you so much.
((ありがとうございます))
You say that dying is meaningless,
（心の声）≪死んだら意味がない
君は　そう言うけど…≫
だったら　ますます　君が行く意味は
なくなってしまうのに…。
but that would mean your coming along is even more meaningless.
Huh?
ん？
（羽村）あっ　いや…。
Oh, nothing!
（山本）サンキュー
フォー　ウエイティング！→
Thank you for waiting!
レンタル料
ギリギリまで値切れたわ。→
I managed to talk down our ship's rental fee.
浮いたお金で　今夜は豪遊ね！
（哲馬）考えるだに無謀だな。→
We're going all out with this extra money tonight.
This plan is foolish.
Taking on a hundred cruisers with just one ship
たった１隻で
１００隻の武装艦を相手に→
and with only seven of us.
しかも　僅か７名で…。
（山本）問題ないわ。
That's not a big deal.
Magic can increase our speed and defense
速度と防御は
魔法で強化できるし→
航行の際も　完全に船体を隠せる。
as well as conceal our ship's approach.
However, Kusaribe magic will not be effective in the vicinity of the fleet.
（夏村）しかし
艦艇が現在いる海域では→
鎖部の魔法を使えません。
事実上→
The fact remains that only Hanemura will be able to approach it.
羽村以外は　艦艇に近づけない。
（山本）ふふふっ。
That's exactly the point Fuwa Mahiro's plan addresses.
そのためにあるのが
不破真広の作戦でしょう？
If we can force the fleet into an area where Kusaribe magic is viable,
艦艇を　魔法が使える海域に→
引きずり出せれば
勝機はあるじゃない。
we'll have a chance.
You would place that much faith in the boy?
（哲馬）小僧の戯れ言を
そこまで信じるか？
（山本）責任者として
ここまで来ると言ってるし→
Well, he even insisted on taking the lead himself.
イレギュラーがあったら
そのつど　修正させるわよ。
If anything unexpected comes up, I'll have him make adjustments.
（夏村）彼らが来ることを
あんなに反対していたのに→
At first, you most certainly did not want them to come along,
随分と肩入れしているようですね。
yet now, you support their decision.
I guess I do, huh?
（山本）わっ！　やだ　ほんとだ。
ふふっ　特別な時に→
"In a special place at a special time," was it?
特別な場所にいる少年たち…　か。
Well, no point in worrying!
（山本）まっ
心配しても　しかたないって。→
We should start getting ready.
早く準備を進めましょう！
（哲馬）うわっ！　なっ　何をする!?
Wh-What are you doing?
あと　問題は　その格好よね。
We can't have you going dressed like this.
（潤一郎）
う～ん…　ちょっと多すぎかなぁ。
This might be going overboard.
（潤一郎）これは置いてこうか。
I guess I could leave it behind.
こっ　これ→
Is this full of magazines?
全部　写真集ですか？
うん。
Yeah.
Visualizing and then animating static images is good for improving focus.
静止画像で
揺れるさまを想像すると→
いい精神統一になるんだ。
しかも　データじゃダメなんだよね。
絶対に紙。
They can't be virtual images either.
It's got to be on paper.
Ah, I see.
あっ…　そうですか。
吉野君は　随分　荷物が少ないね。
You aren't bringing much luggage.
Yeah.
はい。　準備とか心構えとか→
Mahiro showed me
どれだけ綿密にしても
意味がないって→
how useless it would be to try to prepare myself in any way.
真広に教わりましたから。　うわっ。
Whoa!
（潤一郎）葉風ちゃん。
葉風さん。
Hakaze?
Miss Hakaze!
（葉風）心構えのない者が→
I can't believe that someone
決戦の地に出向こうとはな。
would head into a decisive battle utterly unprepared.
あぁ～あ　ただの女の子だな。
Jeez.
I guess she's just a girl after all.
もうすぐ
本当に　そうなるんですね。
Soon enough, I suppose she really will be.
（潤一郎）
ああ　作戦がうまくいけばね。→
Yeah,
if everything goes as planned.
はじまりの樹を倒せば
葉風ちゃんだけではなく→
If the Tree is defeated,
not only Hakaze
but the entire clan will be unable to use magic.
鎖部一族は　魔法を使えなくなる。
（左門）確か　この辺りで
待っているはずなのだが…。
She should be around here, waiting for us.
（羽村）はぁ　はぁ…。
≪（山本）団体さ～ん→
Everyone! Over here, over here!
こっち　こっち～！→
おお～！
溶け込んでるなぁ…。
She fits right in.
How humiliating!
（哲馬）屈辱！
耐えてください。
Please bear with it.
大舞台を前に　鎖部の鉄の意志が
試されているのです。
Our clan's iron resolve is being tested before the grand finale.
Let's run through the plan.
じゃあ　作戦を　ざっと洗い直すか。
だいたい
御柱から３０キロ離れた地点→
Approximately 300 km from the Pillar,
この艦艇の輪がある所から
１０キロ以上離れた付近に→
or a little over 10 km from the ring of cruisers,
we will make our stand.
こちらは陣取る。　そこで　まずは→
Then we'll focus on striking the survey ships.
この　いちばん内側にいる調査船に
手を打つ必要がある。
羽村が海中を高速移動して
メンバーの何人かを→
Hanemura will transport several of us underwater to them.
調査船へ運ぶ。
はい！
Understood!
It should be Junichiro, Yamamoto, and Natsumura.
潤一郎と　山本　夏村
という手はずだな。
（山本）よろしくね～。
いや　夏村は　左門と動いてもらう。
Take good care of me!
No, Natsumura should support Samon.
代わりに
俺と吉野だ。
Yoshino and I will go instead.
Hey, wait a minute.
（山本）ちょっと　あなたたち！
調査船は武装してねぇし→
The survey ships are unarmed,
and their crews are noncombatants.
乗員も非戦闘員だろ？
しかも　魔法は使えねぇ。
Plus, Kusaribe magic will be unusable,
だったら　腕っぷしだけの問題だ。
（山本）でも…。
so it'll come down to physical combat.
But...
The task I've given Samon is difficult.
左門に任せたミッションは
骨が折れる。
I figured he could use some help.
もう一人　必要だと考えてた。
夏村には　そっちに回ってもらう。
That'll be you, Natsumura.
いいな？
Got it?
（夏村）分かった。
Very well.
決まりだ。
潤一郎　吉野　ちょっと来てくれ。
Then it's decided!
Junichiro and Yoshino, come with me.
羽村　お前もだよ。
（羽村）あっ　ああ。
Hanemura, you too.
O-Okay.
We're counting on you!
今回のキモは　お前なんだからな。
しっかりしろよ。
Do your best.
I will.
（羽村）分かってる。
パキッ
≫（山本）あら　どうしたの？
Oh, what's wrong?
明日は早いんだから
もう休まないと。
We have an early start tomorrow.
You should be resting.
あの…
葉風さん　見ませんでしたか？
Um, have you seen Miss Hakaze?
（左門）寝つけず　ひと泳ぎしてくる
と言っておられたが。
She said she was having trouble sleeping and went for a swim.
あっ　ありがとうございます。
Oh, thank you very much.
あまりに些末な感情が
大局を動かすこともある。
Even the most trivial emotions can affect the overall outcome.
それを見越して
滝川吉野の参加を認めたのか？
Knowing that, you allowed him to accompany us nevertheless?
ふふっ　どうかしらね。
Well, we'll see.
でも　まあ　こういうのは→
Still, no man or woman is immune to the effects of love.
男も女も変わらないのよ。→
Knowing that your loved one is watching means you'll try your best.
好きな子が見てたら
俄然　張り切っちゃうのは。
≫はぁ　はぁ　はぁ。
あっ。
葉風さん→
Miss Hakaze,
ありがとうございます
僕たちの参加を許してくれて。
thank you very much
for allowing us to come.
（葉風）
許したつもりは　一度としてない。
I do not recall ever allowing it!
葉風さん…。
（葉風）お前は→
Miss Hakaze.
You know how I feel about you.
私の気持ちを知っているな。
えっ？
私は　お前にほれている！
I'm in love with you!
葉風さ…。
ほれた男を→
Miss Hakaze.
Is there something wrong with wanting to keep the man I love out of harm's way?
いらぬ危険に巻き込みたくないと
そう願うことの　どこが悪い!?
本当に　まっすぐですね。
バカにしているのか!?
You're so straightforward.
Are you making fun of me?!
僕は　愛花ちゃんの死は→
I think I've come to terms with Aika's death.
受け入れたつもりです。
（葉風）吉野？
Yoshino.
But
だけど　愛花ちゃんの死の
必要性については…。
as far as her reasoning for it goes,
僕とは
まったく関係のないところでの→
I wasn't even considered.
愛花ちゃんの決断。
Aika decided she didn't need my help
僕の助けなど
まったく必要ないと→
and took care of everything on her own.
すべてを自分で片づけた。
それは違う！→
That isn't true!
There wasn't anything you two could have done—
お前たちには
どうすることもできなかっ…。
I know that!
分かっています！
あの娘は
お前たちを思ってこそ…。
She did it because she cared about both of you.
それは分かっています。
だからこそ…→
I know that.
That's why
葉風さんだけじゃない。
it's not just you, Miss Hakaze,
山本さん　羽村さん　潤一郎さん→
but also Miss Yamamoto, Hanemura, Junichiro,
最初は敵だった左門さんたちも→
and even former enemies like Mr. Samon.
不思議な縁で出会って
共同生活をして→
A twist of fate brought us together.
Living together strengthened that bond,
いつしか　とても関わりの強い→
大切な存在になっていった。
and you've all become important to me.
もう僕は　大切な人たちが→
I just
want to be there
大切なことを決めるその瞬間に→
when those I care about make important decisions!
関係のないところに
いたくないんです！
（葉風）吉野…。
Yoshino.
大切な人の戦いを見届けたい。
If those I care about are fighting, I want to be there.
葉風さん…　うわっ！
Miss Hakaze.
（葉風）私は助けんぞ
お前に何があったとしても。
I'm not going to help you
no matter what happens to you.
はい。　助けてもらって→
Right.
If you helped me, and it held you back,
足を
引っ張るようなことになれば→
I couldn't look you in the eye anymore.
もう　こうして　葉風さんと
向き合うことができませんから。
（葉風）分かった。→
All right.
見ていろ。
えっ？
Be sure to watch.
Take a good look at our fight,
私たちの戦いを…　私を見ていろ！
at me!
はい！
I will!
ほらよ　甘いもん追加。
（羽村）ありがとう。
Here, I ordered dessert.
Thank you.
The plan depends on how much energy you can conserve today,
今日の作戦は　お前の体力を→
どれだけ温存できるかに
かかってる。
気合い入れて食えよ。
so eat up.
ゴクッ
（羽村）
ほかの人が絶園の魔法使いなら→
I'm sure if someone else were the mage of Exodus,
もっと簡単に　はじまりの樹を
倒せるんだろうけど…。
we'd have a much easier time with the Tree of Genesis.
そうだな。　多少の犠牲が出ても→
Probably.
The plan would have a better chance,
もっと確実な策をとっただろうな。
うっ…。
even if there were a greater loss of life.
お前は
人が死にまくるような戦いを→
It's not like
you would ever back a plan that involved too many casualties.
許せるようなヤツじゃないからな。
（羽村）迷惑…　かけてるよね。
I'm causing trouble, aren't I?
それも悪くねぇって
思ってるからこそ→
Not really. Everyone agrees with you,
and that's why they accepted this plan.
みんなが乗ったんだろ。
The battle at Mt. Fuji cost so many lives.
さんざん犠牲者の出た
あの富士の戦い。
左門も早河も　多くの人間を
助けたいと願っていた。
Samon and Hayakawa both talked about saving humanity.
きれい事だけで言えば→
If they had the power to do so, maybe there would've been fewer losses,
一人の犠牲者だって
出したくなかったはずだ。
でもな　お前には→
but unlike them, you do have the power to pull it off.
きれい事を
現実にする力があるんだよ。
Mahiro!
マヒド君！
お前　俺が　ここに来ることには
意味がないと言ったな。
Didn't you say my coming along would be meaningless?
（羽村）
うっ…　やっぱ　聞こえてたんだ。
So you did hear me.
But there is meaning in it.
意味ならあるんだよ。　俺は→
I need to see this thing through for myself.
この目で見ておくべきなんだ。
えっ？
Huh?
今の俺は
なんの資格も力もねぇガキだ。
Right now, I'm just a brat without any qualifications or abilities,
けどな　３０年以内に→
but in thirty years, I swear I'll be
in a position to change the world,
必ず世界を変えられる立場に
立ってやる。
この世界を　魔法なんかなくとも→
and I'm going to make it a decent place, with no need for magic!
まっとうな形にしてみせてやる。
世界を変えられる立場って
どんな立場？
What kind of a position would that be?
Who knows?
さあな。　まあ　なんかあるだろ。
そんな　いいかげんな…。
There's gotta be something.
That's so wishy-washy—
うっ！
俺はな　お前が正直→
To be honest, I'm jealous of you!
羨ましいんだよ。
えっ？
今　その資格を持ってるのは
お前だ。
You're the one who can change the world now,
so don't worry about what comes later.
あとのことは考えるな。
失敗しようが
どれだけ犠牲を出そうが→
Even if you fail or it costs many lives,
俺は　お前の味方だ。
I'll be on your side.
I'll make sure I take care of all your mistakes sooner or later.
お前の失敗は
俺が帳消しにしてやる。
こんな大舞台
一生に　二度もねぇぞ。
This is the stage of a lifetime,
せいぜい楽しんでこい。
so enjoy the limelight!
Okay!
（研究者）現在
御柱の周囲に配備された艦艇は→
Over a hundred cruisers are deployed around the Pillar,
１００隻を超え
絶園の魔法使いの攻撃に…。
prepared to respond to any attack by the mage of Exodus...
≪そろそろか。　この難局に→
It's nearly time.
Will Fuwa Mahiro's plan ultimately prove itself unrealistic,
不破真広の作戦が
机上の空論で終わるか→
or will it be the first step in the fight to save the world?
世界を救う最初の一手になるか≫
（早河）あの少年の
持って生まれたものが問われるな。
We can only hope he's up to the task.
（左門）そろそろ
羽村が５人を運び終えたころか。
By now, it is likely that Hanemura has transported those five.
If everything is going as planned, they're probably preparing for the next phase.
（哲馬）予定では　すでに
次の準備に入っているはずです。
Yes.
（左門）うむ。
≫コツコツ　コツコツ（足音）
It's about time for me to head out.
私が出る時間となったようだな。
お似合いですよ。
（葉風）うれしくない褒め言葉だな。
That suits you well.
What an unpleasant compliment.
鎖部の魔法が使えるのは
せいぜい　ここから５キロ先まで。
At best, Kusaribe magic will only work within the next five kilometers.
The Pillar will neutralize our magic if we move any closer to it.
それ以上　御柱に近づけば
無効化されます。→
位置取りには
くれぐれも　ご注意を。
Be mindful of your position.
（葉風）分かった。
Understood.
（葉風）艦艇１００隻
見事　翻弄してみせよう！
Watch me throw the entire fleet into turmoil!
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　ウウーー（サイレン）
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]（船員）
コンタクト！　方位３３０！→
Contact at bearing 330°!
Confirmed visual on the mage of Exodus!
絶園の魔法使い　確認！
（艦長）何ぃ!?
What?
Distance: 4000.
（船員）距離４０００！
まっすぐ突っ込んできます！
He's heading straight for us.
Launch countermeasures!
迎撃開始！
待ってください！→
Captain, wait!
If that much seawater explodes near our ships...
あの質量の海水が
艦の近くで破裂したら…。
うっ…　どうすれば…。
（船員）艦長！
Dammit.
Captain!
バシャッ！
（船員たち）おおっ…。
（船員）舞姫…。
The Dancing Princess saved us?
舞姫に助けられた？
((葉風の扮した絶園の魔法使いが→
Hakaze, disguised as the mage of Exodus,
鎖部の魔法が使える地点から→
will attack the fleet with Kusaribe magic.
目に見える形で
艦隊を攻撃してみせる))
((そして　羽村　お前は反対に→
Then, Hanemura,
you will appear as the Dancing Princess and deflect her onslaught.
舞姫として出て
葉風の攻撃をはね返す))
((実際は　かなり手前で
葉風の魔法は無力化されるから→
Hakaze's magic will be neutralized at a fair distance from the fleet,
so you actually only need to pretend to deflect her attacks.
あくまで　はね返したふりだがな))
((だが　これで　舞姫が艦と御柱を→
But it will fool them
into believing that the Dancing Princess wishes to protect them and the Pillar.
守る気があるって印象づけられる))
（羽村）援護を！
Cover me!
（船員）舞姫が援護を求めている。
The Dancing Princess wants us to cover her.
くっ…　全艦　攻撃！→
All ships, attack!
Target the mage of Exodus!
目標は　絶園の魔法使い！
ボゥン！
バシュー！
ドカーン！
Hanemura will request cover fire from the fleet
and proceed to attack Hakaze.
((羽村は　艦の連中に援護を命じ
葉風への攻撃に向かえ))
The fleet will have no problem launching a full assault on her,
((舞姫が守ってくれるとなれば→
艦の連中は
遠慮なく葉風へ攻撃をかける))
if they think they have the Dancing Princess on their side.
((葉風は
御柱の周りにいる艦すべてが→
Hakaze, go around the ring of ships as you attack them,
お前への攻撃に
参加しやすいよう→
so that the entire fleet engages you.
艦が展開している輪に
沿うように飛べ))
ドカン！
（葉風）ぐっ！
((標的は小さいし
高速で動いている))
Hakaze will be a small target moving at high speed.
((必ず
前に出たくなってくるはずだ))
The fleet will be drawn forward.
((引きずり出し→
Once they're lured out to the area where Kusaribe magic is effective,
鎖部の魔法が効く範囲に
入ってくれれば　こっちのものだ))
we'll have them.
（左門）艦が引かれはじめたか。
（夏村）左門殿　我々も。
The fleet is breaking formation.
Mr. Samon, we should be on our way.
そうだな。
Indeed.
((羽村　お前は　艦からの
ミサイル攻撃の邪魔にならないよう→
Hanemura, stay away from the fleet's missiles
葉風から距離を取って
攻撃を続けろ))
and continue to attack Hakaze at range.
((あくまで
葉風が艦のいる方に飛ぶのを→
Make it seem like you're preventing her from closing in on the fleet.
妨害しているようにな))
ドカン！
Hakaze, act like the Dancing Princess is pushing you back,
((葉風も
舞姫に押されている格好で→
飛ぶ位置を
少しずつ御柱から遠くし→
and gradually retreat from the Pillar.
少しでも　艦を前に出させるんだ))
You need to draw them out as much as you can.
((そして　重要なのは→
Bear in mind
葉風は　絶園の魔法使いらしい→
that Hakaze must use magic like the mage of Exodus,
and Hanemura, like the Dancing Princess.
羽村は　舞姫らしい
魔法の使い方をすることだ))
（葉風）集中砲火は　うるさいが→
This barrage is tiresome,
but at least I have an endless supply of offerings!
供物の補充には困らんな！
ドカ　ドカ　ドカ！
（葉風）≪まったく
真広は　むちゃをさせる≫
Mahiro sure knows how to work people to their limits.
When will the survey ships fall back?
≪調査船の退避は　まだか…≫
（乗員）
何が起こっている！　連絡は!?
What's going on?
Any contact?
通信障害が発生してます！
≪ガタン！（ドアの音）
There's too much interference!
だっ　誰だ　お前は!?
動くな！
Who the hell are you?
Don't move!
船底に爆発物を取り付けた。
We've rigged your ships with explosives.
If I push this button, every one of them will sink.
これを押せば
確実に　この船は沈む！
We only have one demand.
（山本）こっちの要求は　一つ。
Take the ships as far away from the Pillar as you can.
（潤一郎）大至急　御柱から
できるだけ離れてください。→
それ以上は求めてないよ。
簡単でしょ？
That's all.
Simple, right?
It's not safe here anyway.
それに　ここも安全じゃないし。
ガン！
ザバーン！
（哲馬）行け！
（葉風）行け！
Go!
We're counting on you, Hanemura!
頼みます　羽村さん！
Now, keep going until you're clear of the Pillar.
そのまま　まっすぐ
御柱から離脱するんだ。
≪任せたぞ　羽村！≫
It's all on you, Hanemura!
ガキン！
（哲馬）うっ…。
（葉風）哲馬！→
Tetsuma, if you can't keep up, they'll see through us!
精彩を欠けば気付かれるぞ！
（哲馬）くっ！
（葉風）
≪見えているか？　私の戦いが≫
Are you watching me as I fight, Yoshino?
≪吉野≫
調査船の退避は　じきに終了だ。
The evac operation is just about complete.
とうとうだね。
ああ。
It's come down to this.
Yeah.
あいつと御柱の一騎打ちだ。
It'll be between the Pillar and him.
≪葉風さん…≫
Miss Hakaze.
バキュン！
吉野～～!!
Yoshino!
これが御柱。→
So this is the Pillar.
ひるむな。→
Don't flinch.
ここから先は　誰の助けもない。
No one can help you now.
（羽村）僕だけの戦いなんだ。
This is my fight and mine alone!
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
Here's your takeout!
Damn it! Something's missing...
Here's lunch.
Something critical!
Do you like pickled ginger?
（店員）はい　牛Ｗ　持ち帰り！
くそっ！
Oh, that's obvious.
何かが足りない！
決定的な何かが…。
Where else?
Don't say it!
I'm happy for you.
Episode 24
To Each, Their Own Tale